<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!--This file is part of Chummer5a.

  Chummer5a is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
  it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
  the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
  (at your option) any later version.

  Chummer5a is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
  GNU General Public License for more details.

  You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
  along with Chummer5a.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.

  You can obtain the full source code for Chummer5a at
  https://github.com/chummer5a/chummer5a
-->
<chummer xmlns="" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema programs.xsd">

  <programs>
    <!-- Region Kill Code -->
    <!-- End Region -->
    <program>
      <name>Abduction</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: Owner
      Effect: When the drone’s sensorsare used to make an Observe in Detail action or to perform active targeting, it gets a dicepool bonus equal to the AI’s Depth. The Clearsight autosoft rating must be equal to the AI’s Depth or 6, whichever is lower. This advanced program can be shared using an RCC using an autosoft program slot, but the AI must also be running on the RCC. Standard RCC autosoft sharing rules apply.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Authority</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: 1
      Effect: Authority helps the AI convince devices that its orders are coming from a trusted and privileged source: the owner. The AI receives a bonus equal to its Depth to its Spoof Command actions against a marked icon’s devices.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Cascade</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: 2
      Effect: Any time an AI with this program running fails an Attack action against a sufficiently marked icon, it gains a +1 dice pool bonus on future Attack tests against that target and reduces damage taken from failed Attack actions against the target by the same amount. This bonus can stack up a number of times equal to the AI’s Depth. If the program is quit at any time, all accumulated bonuses vanish. They also vanish after twenty-four hours, as targets make adjustments and the old information becomes invalid.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Eguchi Smile</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: Owner
      Effect: AIs with this program can use the Disguise and Impersonation skills to pose as a metahuman on the Matrix. They may also impersonate other personas with this Program. This disguise doesn't affect Matrix Perception test results. While interacting strictly on the Matrix, Eguchi Smile also adds the AI's Depth as a dice pool bonus to Acting and Influence skill group tests. This Program cannot provide bonuses towards targets in meatspace.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Fnord</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: 1
      Effect: Any marked non-sapient entity—agent, IC, technocritter, or feral AI—that fails to garner any net hits against an AI with the Fnord program on its first Matrix Perception Test cannot perform any further Matrix Perception Tests against the AI for as long as it remains in that host or on that grid. If a security spider or other IC icon marks the AI, no Matrix Perception Test is required, and the AI is automatically spotted.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Medic</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: 3
      Effect: This program allows the AI to reroute power through pathways metahuman minds couldn’t begin to think of. The AI makes a Software + Depth [Data Processing] (2) Test. The targeted persona heals a number of boxes of Matrix damage equal to the number of hits beyond the threshold. This cannot repair damage dealt to a technomancer’s Living Persona, but does work on an AI’s Core. The Medic program can only be used on a set of “wounds” once. Loading this program is a simple action, but using it to heal damage is a complex action.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Nyetworking</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: 2
      Effect: Any marked persona or icon that is on the same grid as the AI suffers a noise penalty equal to the Depth of the AI until the device is rebooted, or either the marked target or AI leaves the grid. Nyetworking interferes with any Matrix traffic in or out of the target as the AI chooses. This penalty also applies to any Matrix actions made against the marked device until the device is rebooted. If the noise generated by the AI is higher than the Device Rating of its target, the device temporarily loses any wireless bonus.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Poke</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: 1
      Effect: For each successful Opposed Test made against a target device’s Firewall, the AI receives a cumulative +1 dice pool bonus to Crash Program actions against the target. This bonus can stack up a number of times equal to the AI’s Depth. If the program is quit at any time, all accumulated bonuses vanish. They also vanish after twenty-four hours, as targets make adjustments and the old information becomes invalid.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Psychotropic Feedback</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: 2
      Effect: If the AI inflicts Matrix damage on a sufficiently marked target, the defender must roll their Willpower + Firewall. The Biofeedback Filter program adds its bonus as well. Use the AI’s Depth as the threshold for this test. If the defender fails, she is afflicted with a psychotropic effect of the AI’s choosing.
      Psychotropic IC inflicts a short-term adjustment lasting for (Depth) hours. This may include effects such as aversions to certain objects or activities, desire for a certain product, complacency or lethargy, guilt, paranoia, phobias, and so on. These may be associated with a specific trigger, such as an aversion to the Matrix, an insatiable urge to eat Nerps, a phobia of trolls, or frothing rage at the sight of Lone Star officers.
      Short-term memory loss is also an option. When resisting these urges, use the target’s missing hits on the resistance test as the threshold, or as the threshold to recall forgotten memories with a Memory Test.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Rootkit</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: 1
      Effect: This program makes the AI much more effective at hiding its presence in the Matrix, allowing it to become nearly invisible to other Matrix users. Marked icons that make Matrix Perception Tests against the AI suffer a negative dice pool modifier equal to the character’s Depth. The effects of this program end each time the AI performs an Attack action. A successful Hide action restarts Rootkit’s functionality.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Rust</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: 1
      Effect: Any time an icon inflicts Matrix damage on an AI running this program (or to its device), reduce one of its Matrix Attributes by 1, chosen by the AI. This effect is cumulative, down to a rating of 0 and lasts until the device is rebooted. This program doesn’t affect living personas or hosts.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Shunt</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: Owner
      Effect: Before resisting Matrix damage to its device, an AI running the Shunt program can choose to redirect some incoming Matrix damage away from the device to its Core Condition Monitor. After resisting the damage, the AI can distribute as many boxes of damage as it wants to its Core Condition Monitor instead of its home device. This program is only usable if the AI has a home device and is running on it. As a bonus, all Matrix Damage taken to the AI’s home device or Core Condition Monitor is reduced by 1. If damage is shunted to both tracks, the damage reduction occurs in both monitors. This effect does not stack with Ironclad.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Teergrube</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: None
      Effect: Any persona that uses an action requiring the Cybercombat or Hacking skill against the AI has its link jammed open, link-locking them. For each mark the target has on the AI, the AI gains a dice pool modifier to prevent a successful Jack Out action equal to its Depth / 3.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Uncertainty</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: 3
      Effect: Any device slaved to a host occupied and marked by the AI suffers unexpected errors more frequently. Anyone interacting with a device slaved to the marked host is treated as though they have the Gremlins quality (p. 81, SR5) at a level equal to half the rating of the AI’s Depth.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>Spotter</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: 3
      Effect: Anytime a drone runs or is shared this autosoft it receives an Accuracy bonus on the related weapon equal to the AI’s Depth, up to twice the weapon’s original Accuracy. The Targeting autosoft rating must be at least as high as the AI’s Depth (or 6) for Spotter to work. In addition, Take Aim actions provide an additional bonus on attacks with the related weapon equal to the AI’s Depth. This bonus doesn’t stack. This autosoft can be shared using an RCC using an autosoft program slot, but only if the AI is running on the RCC. Standard RCC autosoft sharing rules apply.</notes>
    </program>
    <program>
      <name>WTLM</name>
      <notes>Marks Required: Owner
      Effect: AIs with this autosoft can use the Impersonation skill to pose as a metahuman towards meatspace targets. While interacting with targets in the physical world, WTLM also adds the AI's Depth as a dice pool bonus to Acting and Influence skill group tests. This Program cannot provide bonuses towards targets in the Matrix, such as personas.</notes>
    </program>
  </programs>
</chummer>
